Guide to the Slavic and East European Collection, Yale University Library, Records of the Curator
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Slavic and East European Collection, Yale University Library, Records of the Curator
1960-2013
RU 1132
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(6 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, reports, bibliographies, administrative files and travel records documenting the activities and operations of the curator of the Slavic and East European Collection at Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library. Slavic and East European Collection
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, bibliographies, administrative files and travel records documenting the activities and operations of the curator of the Slavic and East European Collection at Yale University Library.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Slavic and East European Collection Curator, 2014.
Biographical / Historical
Yale University Library was among the first in America to collect Slavic materials systematically. Joel Sumner Smith, its Associate Librarian in the late 19th century, was one of the very few in his profession who read Russian. The books and serials he acquired today form the core of one of the major holdings in the West. With over 150,000 volumes concerning Central and Southeast Europe, as well as some 600,000 volumes relating to Russia and the states of the former Soviet Union, Yale has one of the five largest collections in the United States. The Slavic Collection acquires about 13,000 titles in the vernacular languages annually; English-language titles are usually acquired separately by the library for the general collection.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Slavic languages
- Records, 1960-2013; Accession 2015-A-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2048
  - Annual reports
    - 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1996-2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual statistics-Slavic reading room (SRR), 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Association of Professional Schools of International Affairs (APSIA), 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baltic internship, 2002-2013 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographic instruction, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bibliographies, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budgets, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Collection development: 1995-1996 allocations, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Collection description and correspondence, 1963, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Condolences, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, events, newspaper lists and documents, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Conference on Baltic Studies, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cooperative project, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Bushkovitch, Paul, 1990-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Inter-Documentation Company (IDC), 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Council on Russian and East European Studies-reports, 1960-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Department of Education grant, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Development, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - East Coast Consortium for Slavic Collections (ECCSC), 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - East Siberia and Russian Far East-Library Assessment Project, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Europe, 1990-2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Endowment, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Friends of the St. Petersburgh Public Library, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Henrik Deych Archive, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - History Department Library Committee-report, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Inter-office memos and letters, 1989-2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - North Causasus and Volga Basin-Library Assessment Project, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Preservation, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rannit, Tatiana research reports, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Recommendations, 1989-2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Russian and East European area studies, 1964-1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Security report, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Slavic collection internship materials, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Slavic Studies collection, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Slavic reading room-personnel, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Slavic and East European Library Fellow
  - Soviet and East European Council, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Tercentennial exhibit, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Travel files
    - Kalingrad, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Moscow, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - University of Virginia Library-Slavic collections, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Western Russia-Library Assessment Project, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)